MAXWELL COOPER

FRONTEND SOFTWARE ENGINEER







PROFILE

Software engineer with particular experience in frontend technologies, specifically using Typescript to build React apps for early-stage startups. Special emphasis on UI/UX design and execution, as well as general app management including DevOps and debugging.

EDUCATION

BROWN UNIVERSITY

2014-2018

Electrical Engineering, Sc.B.

GPA: 3.4

HEREFORD HIGH SCHOOL

2010-2014

GPA: 4.0

TOWSON UNIVERSITY

2013

Multivariable Calculus (MATH275)

GPA: 4.0

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

React, TypeScript, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Docker, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, Python, Java

PROFESSIONAL

Git, Jira, VS Code, AWS products (EC2, CloudFront, RDS, Lambda, CodePipeline, CloudWatch), Agile (Scrum), TEFL

TESTS

SAT: 2340 ACT: 34

SAT II: Chem 800, Math II 800, Physics 780

EXPERIENCE

INFONDRIAN

Frontend Software Engineer, January 2020-Present

- Built and partially designed frontend SPA for a cloud-based radiation oncology chart-checking software startup from start to finish using React Typescript (including custom hooks) and asynchronous API calls/different custom features, along with many different imported libraries such as styledcomponents, Axios, react-router-dom, D3.js, Moment.js, socket.io, js-cookie, qs, Material UI, and others.
- Completed backend work (NodeJS and TypeScript) including writing Postman API tests, debugging 500 internal server errors, SQL queries (Sequelize) to the database, writing GET/POST functions from the API route to the response and AWS Lambda functions on a separate repository that execute on the database itself.
- Architected entire frontend CI/CD pipeline with GitHub trigger from dev to prod including testing stage using AWS CodePipeline as well as DNS networking using AWS Route 53 and AWS Cloudfront to point to an S3 bucket.
- Used various Docker containers including running a local PostgreSQL database, an Nginx proxy for a secondary API, and frontend testing using Docker containers running CodeceptJS and Selenium WebDriver.
- Set up authentication for React app using Auth0 and later transitioning to a custom login page with Amazon Cognito.
- Created initial iteration of Python-based secondary API for HIPAA compliance.

INTUS CARE

Frontend Software Engineer, October 2019-January 2020

- One of two software engineers to develop the frontend of a caregiver management application for a Brown startup company, a finalist of the Brown Venture Prize and 2019 MassChallenge winner.
- Used React Native with TypeScript, MongoDB/Azure for the database/server, and Storybook to create components.

OTHER

GOTOCO TEFL VOLUNTEER PROGRAM

Summer/Fall 2019 - Beijing, China

• Taught English to adult Chinese students while earning TEFL certificate.

COLLEGE CRUSADES FTC STUDENT ADVISOR

2018-2019 - Providence, RI

• Mentored at-risk high school students in robotics competition against other schools